<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cores on VHDL News</title>
    <link>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cores on VHDL News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:46:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NEORV32: 32-bit RISC-V soft-core CPU and microcontroller-like SoC in VHDL</title>
      <link>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/36/</guid>
      <description>The NEORV32 Processor is a customizable microcontroller-like system on chip (SoC) that is based on the RISC-V NEORV32 CPU. The project is intended as auxiliary processor in larger SoC designs or as ready-to-go stand-alone custom microcontroller that even fits into a Lattice iCE40 UltraPlus 5k low-power FPGA running at 24 MHz.
Special focus is paid on execution safety to provide defined and predictable behavior at any time. Therefore, the CPU ensures that all memory access are acknowledged and no invalid/malformed instructions are executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VHDL/Verilog Cryptography cores incl. co-simulation with openSSL through GHDLs VHPIdirect</title>
      <link>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/24/</guid>
      <description>Cryptography IP-cores &amp;amp; tests written in VHDL / Verilog.
The components in this repository are not intended as productional code. They serve as proof of concept, for example how to implement a pipeline using only (local) variables instead of (global) signals. Furthermore they were used how to do a VHDL-to-Verilog conversion for learning purposes.
The testbenches to verify AES and CTR-AES are examples how useful GHDLs VHPIdirect is. They use openSSL as reference models to check the correctness of the VHDL implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microwatt and GHDL - An Open Hardware CPU written in VHDL, Synthesized with Open Source Tools</title>
      <link>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 06:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vhdl.github.io/news/cores/21/</guid>
      <description>Microwatt and GHDL - An Open Hardware CPU written in VHDL, Synthesized with Open Source Tools
Speakers: Anton Blanchard, IBM &amp;amp; Tristan Gingold, CERN
Microwatt is a 64 bit POWER OpenISA soft processor, written in VHDL. Over time it has grown from supporting Micropython, to Zephyr and most recently Linux.
From its original inception, Microwatt has relied heavily on GHDL, the Open Source VHDL simulator. GHDL has very recently added synthesis support and together with Yosys and Nextpnr allows for a completely open source toolchain for FPGAs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>